Craig Taylor 80 Edward Tyler Road, London, SE12 9QF (+44)7908 795936

craigtaylor89@yahoo.co.uk
https://www.craig-taylor.co.uk

Profile

Front-End/ Games Developer with experience using C++/C#, Unity3D HTML, CSS, SASS, Javascript, React.js, Node.js, Express.js, Wordpress, MySQL, PHP and Git.

Passionate and self-driven to develop applications and video games that deliver a lasting impact amongst our target audiences with the means to learn, accept challenges and persevere.

Personal Projects

Udacity Capstone Project | Github Link | Javascript, Node.js, Express.js, Jest, Webpack

 Developed a search engine based on the user's intended travel destination as a keyword, the date of arrival and optionally return before retrieving a picture and the weather forecast of the said destination.

Dungeon Escape | Github Link | Unity3D, C#

- Developed a game called Dungeon Escape is part of a Unity approved course to expand knowledge in C# and utilise the intermediate functionality of the game engine.
- Intentionally will become an ongoing personal project to implement further mechanics and enemy varieties as a resemblance of the Metroidvania genre.

Qualifications

Udacity Front-end Developer Nanodegree – Pass
BA (Hons) Game Design – Tiga Accredited – First Class Honours
BTEC National Diploma for Games Development – DDD (Distinction, Distinction, Distinction)
BTEC First Diploma in IT – Merit
BTEC Introductory Diploma for IT at Work – Distinction

Work Experience

<u>SportStream Ltd – Junior Front-End Developer</u>

April 2021 to Present

SportStream Ltd. is a British sport streaming company for amateur and semi-professional sports. Based in London, England, United Kingdom

- Created a website exclusively for the business from the ground up using React.js and Gatsby.js respectively to develop a fast loading application based on the Photoshop design template.
- Utilised industry-standard practices that involve responsive layouts using media queries to showcase an accessible website application for desktop, laptop, tablet and mobile users.
- Developed and maintained reusable React components to cut down development time for new pages.
- Collaborated with stakeholders and co-workers on issues that needed resolving and made fixes based on complexity and impact.

TT Fusion Ltd – QA Tester

July to November 2015

LEGO Marvel's Avengers -PS3/PS4/Xbox 360/Xbox One/Wii U

TT Fusion Ltd. (formerly Embryonic Studios Ltd.) is a British video game developer company and a division of TT Games. Based in Wilmslow, England, United Kingdom

- Conducted Smoke Testing to ensure the player is able to naturally progress from the start of the game without any progression blockers that would ruin the experience.
- Conducted Scripted/Regression/Sweep testing based on Lead QA's instructions and Destructive testing to identify unreported bugs and ensure fixes are in place from Regression testing.
- Observed, analysed and reported evidential bugs using JIRA based on its severity and urgency with Lead QA's approval to ensure upmost quality, challenge and enjoyment upon release.

Other Employment

MMARAP – Lead Game Designer

March 2021 to Present

- Created, designed and documented core gameplay mechanics, theme of the game and the world creation for the game as a whole.
- Led a team of programmers and artists on providing key objectives to complete within a reasonable time-frame using Gantt/Agile.
- Assisted with the recruitment of future volunteers who has key abilities and strong characteristics that relates to key roles within the development team.

Homestead LCI - Barista

November 2020 to February 2021

- Listened to customers' orders and delivered coffee/tea drinks at a reasonable timeframe based on urgency and priority.
- Utilised previous experience as a speciality coffee barista to independently open and close the cafe section throughout the day.
- Communicated with customers in a friendly and professional manner while using coffee knowledge to promote retail sales with advice on brewing techniques.
- Trained colleagues on using the espresso machine to improve workflow and knowledge for the foreseeable future.
- Communicated with colleagues based on ongoing orders to create an effective workflow during peak times.